Guide to the International Comparative Studies records, 1982-2011 and undated UA.25.24.0002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
International Comparative Studies records
1982-2011 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University International Comparative Studies
UA.25.24.0002
10.5 Linear Feet 7 boxes
International Comparative Studies (ICS) is an undergraduate interdisciplinary academic program affiliated with Duke University in Durham, North Carolina. The collection's files document the program's academic mission and operations, chiefly dating from the 1980s to 2011, and comprise course files, correspondence and memos, budget and grant files, alumni information, newsletter files, student work, questionnaires, materials on programming and conferences, and files about related Duke offices such as Trinity Arts and Sciences and Comparative Area Studies.
Arrangement
Records are arranged in order as originally received, in loose topical or functional groups.
Historical Note
Duke University's International Comparative Studies (ICS) is an undergraduate interdisciplinary program that bridges the humanities and social sciences.
Access Restrictions
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their educational records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Conditions Governing Access
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the director of the office of creation and the University Archivist is required for use. (Issued by the Office of the Chancellor, December 1, 1975)
Provenance
The International Comparative Studies records were received as a transfer by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 2012.
Collection Overview
The collection's files document Duke University's International Comparative Studies (ICS) program's academic mission and operations, chiefly dating from the 1980s to 2011. The mateials comprise course files, correspondence and memos, budgets, grant files, awards, ICS programming and conferences, alumni information, newsletter files, student work, questionnaires, and files about related organizations on campus. The latter include Duke administrative offices as well as Comparative Area Studies (CAS).
Aesthetics, Comparative; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University -- History; History -- Comparative method; Humanities -- Comparative method; Humanities -- Study and teaching; International education -- United States; Social sciences -- Comparative method; Sociology -- Comparative method; Durham (N.C.)
- International Comparative Studies files, 1982-2011 and undated
  - Courses Prep, 2005-2006 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    syllabi
  - Comp Area 200 - Old Notes, 2003 (Fall) (Box 1)
    notes, emails, handouts
  - CAS 200 Material, 2003 (Fall) (Box 1)
    texts and syllabi
  - Comp Area 200, 2003 (Fall) (Box 1)
    student papers
  - 200 Class Notes, 2003 (Fall) (Box 1)
    handwritten notes
  - Comp Area 200S - Old Notes, 2004 (Fall) (Box 1)
  - Comp Area 200S - Class Notes, 2004 (Fall) (Box 1)
  - CAS 200S, 2004 (Fall) (Box 1)
    student work
  - 200S Planning, 2004 (Fall) (Box 1)
    forms
  - Programs: Women's Studies, undated (Box 1)
    texts
  - ICS Class Notes, 2007 (Fall) (Box 1)
    handwritten and typed notes
  - ICS 200S - Old, 2007 (Fall) (Box 1)
    handwritten notes and handouts
  - ICS 200S, 2007 (Fall) (Box 1)
    notes, handouts, and student feedback
  - ICS 200S Final Papers, 2007 (Fall) (Box 1)
  - Honors Meetings, 2003-2004 (Box 1)
    emails, thesis proposals
  - Honors - "This is the Active Folder!", 2004 (Spring) (Box 1)
    notes and emails
  - Honors, 2004-2005 (Box 1)
    student proposals
  - Honors Proposals, 2005-2006 (Box 1)
  - ICS 150S, 2006 (Spring) (Box 1)
    notes, emails, thesis proposals
  - Thesis Proposal, 2006-2007 (Box 1)
  - ICS 150S, 2007 (Spring) (Box 1)
    notes
  - ICS 198S, 2008 (Spring) (Box 1)
    notes and thesis proposal
  - Thesis Proposals, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  - 195-196 Prep, 2008 (Spring) (Box 1)
    syllabi and handouts
  - ICS 195 Class, 2006 (Spring) (Box 1)
    notes and student work
  - ICS 195 Prep - Old, undated (Box 1)
  - ICS 195 Class Notes, 2006 (Box 1)
  - ICS 195 Old Notes, 2006 (Box 1)
  - ICS 195 Class, 2007 (Spring) (Box 2)
    notes and student papers
  - ICS 195 Class Notes, 2007 (Spring) (Box 2)
  - 195 Class, 2008 (Box 2)
  - ICS 195 - Old, 2008 (Spring) (Box 2)
    notes, texts, and student papers
  - ICS 195 Prep, 2008 (Spring) (Box 2)
    syllabi and texts
  - ICS 196 Class, 2007 (Spring) (Box 2)
    notes and thesis proposals
  - ICS 196 - Old, 2007 (Spring) (Box 2)
    notes and texts
  - ICS 196 Class, 2008 (Spring) (Box 2)
  - 196 Prep, 2007 (Spring) (Box 2)
    notes and text
  - ICS 197S - Old, 2007 (Fall) (Box 2)
  - ICS Class, 2005 (Spring) (Box 2)
  - CST 125 Student Feeddback, 2002 (Box 2)
    student evaluations
  - Comp Area 125 - Past, 2003 (Spring) (Box 2)
    memos, rosters, and notes
  - Comp Area 125 - Pending, 2003 (Spring) (Box 2)
    grade reports
  - CAS 125 Class, 2004 (Spring) (Box 2)
    grade reports, student evaluations, and assignments
  - Comp Area 125 - Reading, 2004 (Spring) (Box 2)
  - 125 Planning, 2004 (Spring) (Box 2)
  - CAS 125 Class Notes, 2004 (Spring) (Box 2)
  - Comp Area 125 - Old Notes, 2004 (Spring) (Box 2)
    notes, emails, student evaluations
  - CAS 125 Class Notes, 2005 (Spring) (Box 2)
  - ICS Old Notes, 2005 (Spring) (Box 2)
  - 125 Planning, 2005 (Spring) (Box 2)
    article clippings, business cards, notes
  - ICS 495 Class Notes, 2005 (Fall) (Box 2)
  - ICS 495 Old Notes, undated (Box 2)
  - ICS 495 Class, 2005 (Fall) (Box 2)
    notes and student evaluations
  - Study Abroad Committee, 2007-2008 (Box 2)
    minutes
  - CST 150S, 1993 (Box 3)
    thesis evaluations
  - CST 150S, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
    grade reports, memos, letters
  - Thesis Awards, undated (Box 3)
    letters
  - CST 150S, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
  - CST 150S, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - 150S Proposals, 2000 (Spring) (Box 3)
    thesis proposals
  - CST 150S, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - CAS Honors Graduates List, undated (Box 3)
    memos and letters
  - CST 150S, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
    letters and thesis proposals
  - CST 150S, 1996-1997 (Box 3)
  - Historical Documents, undated (Box 3)
  - CST 150S, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - CST 150S, 2001 (Box 3)
  - CST 150 Thesis/Travel Props, 2002 (Box 3)
    thesis proposals and grant applications
  - CST 150S, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
    thesis proposals and evaluations
  - CAS Students, 1994 (Box 3)
    notecards, rosters, graduation program
  - CAS Students, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    notecards, rosters, letters
  - Alumni Mailing List, 1993 (Box 3)
    contact information forms
  - Newsletter items, 1989 (Box 3)
    alumni news forms
  - Alum Newsletter, 1988 (Box 3)
    newsletters
  - Alum Newsletter, 1987 (Box 3)
    newsletter and questionnaires
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 3)
    brochures, course listings, and letters
  - CAS Enrollment and Major Figures, undated (Box 3)
    student data
  - School Policies, undated (Box 3)
    memos
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 3)
    memos, course list, syllabus
  - Award Winner, 1995 (Box 3)
    flier
  - Comparative Area Mailing List, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    mailing lists
  - Course Development Grants, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Course Development Grants, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    letters and memos
  - Course Development Grants, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
  - Course Development Grants, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Course Development Grants, 1994 (Box 3)
    applications
  - Course Development Grants, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Course Development and Grants, 1988 (Box 3)
    letters and applications
  - Workshop, 1992 (Box 3)
  - CST- Career Workshop, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Career Workshop, 1988 (Box 3)
  - CAS: Career Workshop, 1987 (Box 3)
  - CIS- Career Workshop, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Newsletters, undated (Box 3)
  - CAS Alumni Questionnaire Reports, undated (Box 3)
    reports
  - Comparative Area Majors Mailing List, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
    mailing list
  - Comparative Area Graduates, 1984 (Box 3)
    letters and report
  - CAS Students, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4)
    typed index cards and brochure
  - Honor Thesis, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
    letters and roster
  - Honor Thesis Evaluations, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Senior Paper Evaluation, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
  - CAS Honors Program, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4)
  - CAS Summer Grants, undated (Box 4)
    proposal, letters and memos
  - Summer Research Travel Grant, 1990 (Box 4)
    proposals and letters
  - Summer Travel Grants, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Summer Travel Grants, 1992 (Box 4)
  - CST Summer Research Grant, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
    letters and proposal
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4)
  - Student Conferences, undated (Box 4)
    memos and proposals
  - CAS Summer Travel Grants, undated (Box 4)
    letters and proposals
  - CAS Questionnaires, undated (Box 4)
    questionnaires
  - CAS Students, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
    questionnaires and mailing list
  - CAS Students, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
    index cards and questionnaires
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4)
    letters and lists
  - Untitled, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - Letter to Comparative Area Graduates, 1983 (Box 4)
    report
  - Students, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
    lists
  - Conference Grants, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
    proposal, letter and memo
  - Conference Grant, 1990-1991 (Box 4)
    proposal and letters
  - Spring Pre-registration, 1989 (Box 4)
    memos and forms
  - Conference Grant, 1991-1992 (Box 4)
    memos and proposal
  - Symposium Proposals, 1988 (Box 4)
    proposal
  - Symposium Proposals, undated (Box 4)
  - CAS Conference Grants, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    proposal and memos
  - Major's Union, 1988-1989 (Box 4)
    letters and budgets
  - Newsletters and Major Union Funding, undated (Box 4)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 4)
    letters and fliers
  - Untitled, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Non-Position, 2006 (Box 5)
    print-outs and manual
  - Budget FY, 2006-2007 (Box 5)
    budget, lists and letters
  - Budget FY, 2010-2011 (Box 5)
    budgets and instructions
  - Budget, 2009-2010 (Box 5)
    budgets and memos
  - Budget FY, 2008-2009 (Box 5)
    budgets, memos and print-out
  - Budget FY, 2007-2008 (Box 5)
    print-outs, memos and manual
  - Budget FY, 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    budgets, manual, and memos
  - Budget, 2006-2007 (Box 5)
    letters, lists and manual
  - DUS, 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    memos and manual
  - Budget FY, 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    budgets, letters and manual
  - Budget, 2003-2004 (Box 5)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 5)
    major requirements lists
  - JHFC Info, undated (Box 5)
    itenerary and flier
  - Dean's Office (Trinity), undated (Box 5)
    handouts and memo
  - Special Projects (External), undated (Box 5)
  - Maital Guttman (Wed @ Ctr), 2005 (Box 5)
    letters and forms
  - McGrew, Porangui (Wed @ Ctr), 2005 (Box 5)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 5)
  - Career Workshop (Box 5)
    forms and letters
  - Untitled, 1998 (Box 5)
    letters, lists and fliers
  - CAS Workshop, 1995 (Box 5)
    letters, lists and brochures
  - Career Dev. Workshop, 1989-1990 (Box 5)
  - Scott Stephenson, undated (Box 6)
    application
  - Urry, John Social Networks, Travel and Talk, undated (Box 6)
    lists and fliers
  - Letters of Appointment, undated (Box 6)
  - International Comparative Studies, undated (Box 6)
  - Charity Greene, undated (Box 6)
    evaluation materials
  - Student Exception Requests, undated (Box 6)
  - International Affairs Committee, 2003 (Box 6)
    handouts and report
  - CAS Info, 2002 (Box 6)
    memos, lists and notes
  - CAS Staff Assistant Job, undated (Box 6)
    notes, letters and resumes
  - DUS Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 6)
  - MA Programs, undated (Box 6)
    letters, notes and print-outs
  - Area and International Studies (Box 6)
    print-outs
  - Workshop, 2004 (Box 6)
  - DUS Correspondence, 2002 (Box 6)
    letters, notes and lists
  - Untitled, undated (Box 6)
  - John Florin, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 2002-2003 (Box 6)
    budget, letter and manuals
  - Past Notes, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Memos, Etc., 2003-2004 (Box 6)
    letters and list
  - CAS Old Notes, undated (Box 6)
  - Faculty Scholar Nomination, undated (Box 6)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 6)
  - Check Sheets, undated (Box 6)
    print-out
  - CAS Old Notes, 2004 (Box 6)
    memos, budgets and outlines
  - Old Course Lists, 2009 (Box 6)
  - QEP GAP, 2008-2009 (Box 6)
  - Poniatowska, Elena, "The Last Turkey", undated (Box 6)
  - Budget, 2007-2008 (Box 6)
    forms, lists, letters and print-outs
  - Future ICS Business, undated (Box 6)
    lists and notes
  - Staff and Steering Committee, 2007 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 2009 (Box 6)
  - CAS Budget, undated (Box 6)
    forms, lists, letters and budgets
  - ICS Students, 2007 (Box 6)
    rosters
  - Alumni Workshop, 2006 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 6)
  - International Affairs Committee, 2007-2008 (Box 6)
    lists and report
  - SACS, undated (Box 6)
    notes and print-outs
  - DUS Business, 2008 (Box 6)
  - Budget, 2010-2011 (Box 6)
    notes, letters, budget and report
  - Graduation, 2005-2006 (Box 6)
    program and remarks
  - Steering Committee, undated (Box 6)
    notes, letters and proposal
  - Temporary Teaching Position, undated (Box 6)
  - ICS Advisors, 2006-2007 (Box 7)
  - ICS Advisors, 2005-2006 (Box 7)
    emails
  - CAS Advisors, 2003-2004 (Box 7)
  - CAS Advisors, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - CAS Brochures, undated (Box 7)
    brochures
  - CAS Faculty, 2003 (Box 7)
  - CASMU, undated (Box 7)
    lists and emails
  - ICS Steering Committee, 2007-2008 (Box 7)
  - ICS Steering Committee, 2006-2007 (Box 7)
    emails and lists
  - ICS Steering Committee, 2005-2006 (Box 7)
  - CAS Steering Committee, 2004-2005 (Box 7)
  - CAS Steering Committee, 2003-2004 (Box 7)
  - CAS Steering Committee, 2002-2003 (Box 7)
  - Career Workshop, 2008 (Box 7)
    list
  - Career Workshop, 2007 (Box 7)
    print-outs, handouts, emails and lists
  - Career Workshop, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Career Workshop, 2005 (Box 7)
  - Career Workshop, 2004 (Box 7)
  - Career Workshop, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Career Workshop, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Career Workshop, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Career Workshop Brochures, undated (Box 7)
  - Sophmore Majors Fair, undated (Box 7)
    emails, reports and lists
  - Adds/Revisions of Red Courses, undated (Box 7)
  - Course Approvals - Study Abroad, undated (Box 7)
    proposals
  - Curriculum Committee, 2006 (Box 7)
    letter
  - Course Offerings (Lists - Past/Present), undated (Box 7)
  - Curriculum Code - Approve/Disapprove, undated (Box 7)
  - Program Petitions, 2003 (Box 7)
  - ICS Crosslisting Project, 2005 (Box 7)
    emails, forms and lists
  - Crosslists - Approvals, undated (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 7)